
[
    {
        "question": "The process where the weathered rock sink ‘insides’ is called ......",
        "options": [
            "Landslides",
            "Slumping",
            "Solution",
            "Erosion"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "...... is universal solvent.",
        "options": [
            "Soil",
            "Water",
            "Carbon",
            "Oxygen"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Sea water being ...... creates holes in the rocks near the coast.",
        "options": [
            "Crystalline",
            "Alkaline",
            "Oxide",
            "Carbonate"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Water is a ...... solvent.",
        "options": [
            "Blue",
            "Universal",
            "Water",
            "Carbon"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Holes formed in the rocks due to solution looks like ......",
        "options": [
            "A large",
            "A cave",
            "A honeycomb",
            "A cliff"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Biological weathering occurs because of ......",
        "options": [
            "High temperature",
            "Frost",
            "Crystal growth",
            "Living organism"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Ants, rats, rabbits, snakes, worms etc. make burrows in the ground. These animals are called ...... animals.",
        "options": [
            "Domestic",
            "Herbivores",
            "Burrowing",
            "Terrestrial"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "...... occurs in rocks which have iron content in them.",
        "options": [
            "Carbonation",
            "Oxidation",
            "Disintegration",
            "Solution"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Complete the chemical equation: [ H_2O + CO_2 = ]",
        "options": [
            "( H_2CO_3 )",
            "( H_2CO_2 )",
            "( H_2CO )",
            ""
        ],
        "answer": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Chemical weathering is more effective in humid climate.",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "answer": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Minerals in the rocks expand due to ......",
        "options": [
            "Water",
            "Heat",
            "Snow",
            "Rainfall"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Which weathering is dominant in arid climates?",
        "options": [
            "Mechanical",
            "Chemical",
            "Biological",
            "Landslide"
        ],
        "answer": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "...... is formed due to chemical precipitation.",
        "options": [
            "Conglomerate",
            "Limestone",
            "Sandstone",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not an example of oxidation?",
        "options": [
            "Apple slices turning brown",
            "Breaking of glassware",
            "Rusting of iron",
            "Moistening of table salt"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Oxidation occurs in rocks in areas with high ......",
        "options": [
            "Rainfall",
            "Temperature",
            "Altitude",
            "Pressure"
        ],
        "answer": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Name the process: Iron in the rocks + water and oxygen",
        "options": [
            "Carbonation",
            "Exfoliation",
            "Oxidation",
            "Solution"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Find the odd one.",
        "options": [
            "Wind",
            "Running water",
            "Biological weathering",
            "Glaciers"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Complete the sentence: Water + Carbon Dioxide = ......",
        "options": [
            "Carbonic acid",
            "Hydrochloric acid",
            "Acetic acid",
            "Acid rain"
        ],
        "answer": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "The process of carbonation is more prominent in the ...... rocks.",
        "options": [
            "Sandstone",
            "Igneous",
            "Hard",
            "Limestone"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "At ...... in Ahmadnagar district limestone gets precipitated chemically.",
        "options": [
            "Wada",
            "Wadgaon Darya",
            "Allahabad",
            "Malin village"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "The process of outer layer of rock fall apart from the main rock is called ......",
        "options": [
            "Oxidation",
            "Exfoliation",
            "Alkaline crystallization",
            "Precipitations"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "The reddish coloured layer formed on the rocks is called ......",
        "options": [
            "Solution",
            "Red colour",
            "Rust",
            "Red soil"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not responsible for Mechanical weathering?",
        "options": [
            "Crystal growth",
            "Release of pressure",
            "Frost",
            "Moss"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Because of solution, alkalis in rock dissolve and make them ......",
        "options": [
            "Even",
            "Saturated",
            "Brittle",
            "Crusty"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Many landforms are formed due to the ......",
        "options": [
            "External movements",
            "Internal movements",
            "Vertical movements",
            "Horizontal movements"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    }
]
